Kevin Justin Williams

Santa Monica, CA | kevinjustinwilliams@gmail.com | 917.345.0594 | www.kevinjwilliams.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer. Led to coding and the power of immersive and interactive applications through two aspects of EdTech: executive education and consulting. From executive education, I saw how virtual avatars in curated online environments can facilitate interaction, deliver content and enable retention in new ways. From consulting, I realized how technology can help apply frameworks to vastly different scenarios at scale globally.

Javascript | Ruby | Rails | jQuery | SQL| HTML | CSS | Postgres | MongoDB | Express.js | Angular.js | Node.js | MVC | Industry Analysis | Case Analysis | Organization Analysis | Argument Analysis | Scenario Comparison | Data In Decision Making (A/B Testing, Expected Value, Conditional Probability) | Positioning Analysis

BizDev | Client Management | Brand Positioning | Professional Development | Project Management | User Experience

EXPERIENCE

Oct '15 CODED PROJECTS | GENERAL ASSEMBLY

LOS ANGELES, CA

Dec '15

- <u>DroneHive</u> Drone fleet management app that displays data. Code/Tools: MEAN Stack, D3.js, Heroku
- <u>Bundlr</u> Returns top 10 search results from YouTube, Twitter & Reddit, on 3-person team. Responsible for Facebook authorization, OAuth and Users Controller. Pair programmed MEN Stack together
- VRSEatile Netflix for virtual reality streaming content, designed to be an extension of Netflix or VRSE.
 Code/Tools: Ruby, Rails, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bcrypt, Bootstrap, Heroku
- UseOfForceAR A 2-player FPS augmented reality demo game. Code: Javascript, HTML and CSS

EdTech STANFORD GRADUATE SCHOOL OF BUSINESS PALO ALTO / LOS ANGELES, CA

Feb '15 - Teaching Assistant, ExecEd LEAD Program: Corporate Innovation

Present Leveraging a virtual campus and avatars, the Stanford GSB LEAD (Learn. Engage. Accelerate. Disrupt.)

Executive Education Program in Corporate Innovation. Each student experiences a virtual campus and navigates their own avatar which interacts with other students and staff

Coach, Psychology of Startup Teams. Course Facilitator, Strategy & Critical Analytical Thinking

EdTech ONIDA INC LOS ANGELES, CA

2010 - 2014 Chief Operating Officer

2006 - 2010 Director of Business Development

NEW YORK, NY

Onida is a seven-person EdTech consulting firm help solve organizational design challenges, initiate and execute leadership development programs. Drove new business in Abu Dhabi, Kuwait and Dubai.

- Closed over 450 clients, developed corporate partners like Goldman Sachs & Perella Weinberg Partners
- Managed website (HTML/CSS), CRM software platform, AWS/cloud, and API keys

EDUCATION

Sep '15 - GENERAL ASSEMBLY

LOS ANGELES, CA

Dec '15 Web Development Immersive (WDI)

The WDI (Web Development Immersive) is a full-time 12-week intensive programming bootcamp covering the full-stack, with the goal of preparing students with a solid skill set to enter the workforce as trained developers through over 500+ hours of in class instruction. Four projects are coded in one week sprints and completed by end of program using Agile development in one week sprints per project

LANGUAGES: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | Ruby | SQL TOOLS: Rails | NodeJS | ExpressJS | AngularJS

DATABASES: MongoDB | Postgres | Sequelize

OTHER: jQuery | Git/GitHub | Heroku Deployment | JSON | Bootstrap | DOM Manipulation | Sass |

Responsive Web Design | Client-Server Model | API's | AJAX | JSON | MVC | SocketIO |

Ionic | OAuth | Postman | Gulp Task Manager | BDD with Mocha/Chai | Postico

2001-2003 STANFORD GRADUATE SCHOOL OF BUSINESS PALO ALTO, CA

Master of Business Administration

• GPA: N/A (The GSB does not calculate GPAs)

1994-1998 MOREHOUSE COLLEGE ATLANTA, GA

Bachelor of Arts, cum laude, Dean's List

• UGPA 3.5/4.0, Major: Economics (3.9/4.0), Minors: Mathematics & Sociology